# **CHIMA PRECIOUS CHINONSO**

# **Data Analyst**

(+234)07085886404

Lagos Nigeria.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/precious-chima-34b40b22a

apstheinze3@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Skilled data analyst with years of industry experience in collecting, organizing, interpreting and disseminating various types of statistical/analytical figures. Prolific presenter and confident communicator with the ability to circulate information clearly, efficient and beneficial for end users. Creative in finding solutions to problems and determining modification for optimal use of organizational data.

## Areas of Expertise/Skills

- Data cleaning and preparation
- Data Analysis/Database
   Management (MYSQL, EXCEL)
- Dashboards and reports
- Creating data visualization (EXCEL/POWERPOINT, POWER BI, TABLEAU)
- Statistical knowledge
- Analyzing and interpreting data (EXCEL, GOOGLESHEETS)
- User Interface (UI) design and development
- Excellent Verbal and written communication.
  - Ability to work with team effectively

# **Professional Experience**

# **EVERCHRISTY INTERNATIONAL LIMITED (EILIT) Junior Data Analyst**

(Intern)

2017-2018

- Performed advanced analytics functions Including data modeling and prescriptive analysis using Excel, SQL
- Analyze, interpret data sets using statistical process and determine proper repair technique to be used.
- Utilized techniques and business intelligence (Power Bi) to create dashboards and reports to address business problems and streamline processes.
- Developed long term pricing experiment which improved customer value by 15%
- participate in database management with other team members.
- Built operational reporting in TABLUEU to identify areas of improvement, develop and implement the budget for the
  other department.
- Maintain the inventory records for equipment and supplies and other production trends.
- Monthly review and presentations of uploaded/analyzed reports.

## **GIFTED VOCATIONAL CONSULT**

Business Analyst 2022 - 2023

- Used data modelling techniques to identify ways in which the organization can operate more effectively.
- Generated meaningful insight from customer data boosting successful demands by 17%
- Worked with finance, sales and operation to update and maintain manuals.
- Review, research and analyze data in various systems to support respective functional area.
- Supervised productivity, devised KPIs, Complete daily paperwork and projects on timely basis.
- Collect data from sales, marketing and finance departments to use in establishing organizational structure.
- Identify, analyze and interpret trends and patterns in complex data sets using EXCEL, POWER BI.

• Organize and disseminate data across departments used to conclude methods' success.

META iv 2023 - present

## **3D Printing Analyst**

• Examine processed engineering data to uncover trends, patterns, and insights. Develop clear and compelling visualizations to communicate findings to relevant stakeholders. Work with executives and other business leaders to identify opportunities for improvements on 3D models and figurines.

- Use graphs, infographics and other methods to visualize data and Create reports for internal team and external clients.
- Regenerated standard operational procedures that improved 5 functional areas and data management.
- Establish KPIs to measure the effectiveness of business decisions on new projects.
- Conduct quality control checks, pinpoint inaccuracies or inconsistencies, and collaborate with the engineering team to resolve any issues, document results and recommend ideal corrective actions.
- Work in close coordination with engineers, data scientists, analysts, and other team members to ensure the seamless
  alignment of engineering data management efforts to provide and schedule preventive maintenance, procurement of
  damaged or worn-out materials needed.
- Data analysis and production/statistical studies to ensure favorable production cost for prototype designs.
- Maintained report with a 98% on time delivery.
- Present detailed and timely reports about the meaning of gathered data to members of the management and help them identify scenarios utilizing modifications in the data sets given.
- Locate and define new process improvement opportunities and detect areas for improvement.

#### **Education& Certification**

**HND. Mechanical Engineering,** Federal Polytechnic Nekede, Imo State, 2021 **OND. Mechanical Engineering,** Federal Polytechnic Nekede, Imo State, 2016